# NICOLE SOENG

1272 Braileigh Lane, Virginia Beach, VA 23455 · 253-230-5082 nicole.soeng@outlook.com

Research, writing, and management professional with a Master's in Public Administration and 5+ years of experience. Managed mentoring program overseeing 60 mentor/mentee matches. Collaborated with professionals on journal articles and publications for scholarly and non-profit organizations, compiling and utilizing quantitative and qualitative data. Presented research findings at an academic conference and created advisory material for a senate committee. Proficient in Microsoft Word, Publisher, Excel, PowerPoint, and Adobe InDesign.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

**JUNE 2022** 

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT WITH MEAN STACK, TEXAS A&M UNIVERSITY

## **EDUCATION**

**JUNE 2011** 

**MASTER OF PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION, EVANS SCHOOL OF PUBLIC AFFAIRS AT UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON** 

GPA 3.66

**JUNE 2007** 

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN SOCIOLOGY, WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY

GPA 3.96

## **EXPERIENCE**

JULY 2016 - PRESENT

## **SEARCH ENGINE EVALUATOR, RATERLABS**

Analyze and rate quality and accuracy of website content; interpret multiple intents for search queries and evaluate the fitness of web results; edit oral and written web content for grammatical errors and critique accuracy of information and sources.

#### **AUGUST 2010 – JUNE 2011**

### **POLICY ANALYST INTERN, LEAGUE OF EDUCATION VOTERS**

Compiled statistics and financial data into charts and graphs; gathered qualitative data through interviews with experts; utilized data to write a report advising a senate committee on expanding early childhood education programs.

#### **JUNE 2010 – AUGUST 2010**

# RESEARCH ASSISTANT INTERN, NORTHWEST FEDERATION OF COMMUNITY ORGANIZATIONS (NFCO)

Compiled quantitative and qualitative data into a research report on Native Healthcare; wrote and edited report for publication.

#### APRIL 2009 – SEPTEMEBER 2009

## **ON-SITE SUPERVISOR, LITERACY IN THE COMMUNITY**

Coordinated and was a lead for program activities for summer tutoring program; recruited students and tutors for program; created promotional and informational program materials.

#### **APRIL 2008 - APRIL 2009**

# AMERICORPS VISTA PROGRAM COORDINATOR, COMMUNITIES IN SCHOOLS OF FEDERAL WAY

Managed 60+ mentors/mentee matches; point person for mentors, families, and school administration; recruited and trained mentors; increased program volunteer force twofold; created and updated program documents and Microsoft Excel databases; created promotional and training materials, including brochures, flyers and newsletters using Microsoft Publisher and Adobe InDesign.

## RESEARCH AND PUBLICATIONS

# Expanding Prekindergarten in Washington: A Proposal for the Early Learning Technical Working Group (Senate Bill 6759) - June 2011

Co-authored with Lauren Hipp, UW Evans School of Public Affairs

Conducted interviews with leaders of various state early learning programs; proposed roll-out of expanded prekindergarten in Washington; estimated expenses and long-term financial gains; proposed funding sources.

# Native Health Underfunded & Promises Unfulfilled – August 2010 (http://allianceforajustsociety.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Native-Health-Underfunded.pdf)

Co-authored with Julie Chinitz, NFCO

Compiled statistical data into charts; conducted and compiled interview data into report.

# School Interrupted: The Educational Experience of Migrant Children – August 2007

Co-authored with Seth Feinberg and Karen Bradley, WWU

Presented research findings and recommendations for improving educational continuity for migrant children at the Society for the Study of Social Problems conference in New York City.